from Air. There was no light left save that of the stars. When they had
understood what made this ghostly noise, and Perl was quiet again, Ralph and
Simon picked him up unhandily and carried him to a shelter. Piggy hung
about near for all his brave words, and the three bigger boys went together to
the next shelter. They lay restlessly and noisily among the dry leaves,
watching the patch of stars that was the opening toward the lagoon. Sometimes a
little cried out from the other shelters, and once a big spoke in the
dark. Then they too fell asleep. A sliver of moon rose over the horizon,
hardly large enough to make a path of light, even when it sat right down on
the water. But there were other lights in the sky that moved fast, winked, or
went out, though not even a faint popping came down from the battle fought
at 10 mi height. But a sign came down from the world of grown-ups, though at
the time there was no child awake to read it. There was a sudden bright
explosion, and corks grew trail across the sky. Then darkness again, and stars.
There was a speck about above the island, a figure dropping swiftly
beneath a parachute, a figure that hung with dangling limbs. The changing winds
of various altitudes took the figure where they would. Then, three miles up,
the wind steadied and bore it in a descending curve round the sky, and
swept it in a great slant across the reef and the lagoon toward the mountain.
The figure fell and crumpled among the blue flowers of the mountainside, but
now there was a gentle breeze at this height, too, and the parachute flopped
and banged and pulled. So the figure, with feet that dragged behind it, slid
up the mountain, yard by yard, puff by puff, the breeze hauled the figure
through the blue flowers, over the boulders and red stones, till it lay
huddled among the shattered rocks of the mountaintop. Here the breeze was fitful
and allowed the strings of the parachute to tangle in foon and the figure sat its
helmeted head between its knees held by a complication of lines. When the breeze
blew the lines would strain taut and some accident of this pole lifted the
head and chest upright so that the figure seemed to peer across the brow of
the mountain. Then each time the wind dropped the lines would slacken and the
figure bowed forward again, sinking its head between its knees. So as the stars
moved across the sky, the figure sat on the mountaintop and bowed and sank and bowed again.
In the darkness of early morning, there were noises by a rock a little way down
the side of the mountain. Two boys rolled out a pile of brushwood and dead
leaves, two dim shadows talking sleepily to each other. They were the twins, on
duty at the fire. In theory, one should have been asleep and one on watch. But
they could never manage to do things sensibly if that meant acting
independently, and since staying awake all night was impossible, they had both
gone to sleep. Now they approached the darker smudge that had been the signal
fire, yawning, rubbing their eyes, treading with practiced feet. When they
reached it, they stopped yawning, and one ran quickly back from brushed wooden
leaves. The other knelt down. I believe it's out. He fiddled with the sticks
that were pushed into his hands. No. He lay down and put his lips close to the
smudge and blew softly. His face appeared, lit redly. He stopped blowing
for a moment. Sam, give us tinderwood.
Eric bent down and blew softly again till the patch was bright. Sam poked the
piece of tinderwood into the hot spot, then a branch. The glow increased, and
the branch took fire. Sam piled on more branches. Don't burn the lot, said Eric.
You're putting on too much. Let's warm up. We'll only have to fetch more wood.
I'm cold. So am I. Besides, it's dark.
All right, then. Eric squatted back and watched Sam make up the fire. He built a
little tent of dead wood. And the fire was safely a light. That was near. He'd
have been waxy, huh? For a few moments, the twins watched the fire in silence.
Then Eric sniggered. Wasn't he waxy about the fire and the pig? Lucky he
went for Jack instead of us. Huh?
Remember old waxy at school? Boy, you are driving me slowly insane. The twins
shared their identical laughter, then remembered the darkness and other
things, and glanced around uneasily. The flames, busy about the tent, drew their
eyes back again. Eric watched the scurrying woodlice that were so
frantically unable to avoid the flames, and thought of the first fire, just down
there, on the steeper side of the mountain, where now was complete
darkness. He did not like to remember it, and looked away at the mountaintop.
Warmth radiated now, and beat pleasantly on them. Sam amused himself by fitting
branches into the fire as closely as possible. Eric spread out his hands,
searching for the distance at which the heat was just bearable. Idily looking
beyond the fire, he resettled the scattered rocks from their flat shadows
into daylight contours. Just there was the big rock and the three stones there,
that split rock, and there beyond was a gap. Just there, Sam. Huh? Nothing. The
flames were mastering the branches. The bark was curling and falling away, the
wood exploding. The tent fell inwards and flung a wide circle of light over
the mountaintop. Sam, huh? Sam. Sam. Sam looked at Eric irritably. The intensity
of Eric's gaze made the direction in which he looked terrible, for Sam had
his back to it. He scrambled around the fire, squatted by Eric, and looked to
see. They became motionless, gripped in each other's arms. Four unwinking eyes
aimed, and two mouths open. Far beneath them, the trees of the forest sighed.
Then roared. The hair on their foreheads fluttered, and flames blew out sideways
from the fire. 15 yards away from them came the plopping noise of fabric blown
open. Neither of the boys screamed, but the grip of their arms tightened and
their mouths grew peaked. For perhaps 10 seconds they crouched like that, while
the flailing fire sent smokes, sparks, and waves of inconstant light over the
top of the mountain. Then, as though they had but one terrified mind between
them, they scrambled away over the rocks and fled. Ralph was dreaming. He had fallen
asleep after what seemed hours of tossing and turning noisily among the
dry leaves. Even the sounds of nightmare from the other shelters no longer
reached him, for he was back to where he came from, feeding the ponies with sugar
over the garden wall. Then someone was shaking his arm, telling him that it was
time for tea. Ralph, wake up. The leaves were roaring like the sea. Ralph, wake
up. What's the matter? We saw the beast plain. Who are you? The twins. We saw
the beast. Quiet, Piggy. The leaves were roaring still. Piggy bumped into him,
and a twin grabbed him as he made for the oblong of paling stars. You can't go
out. It's horrible. Piggy, where are the spears? I can hear that. Quiet then. Lie
still. They lay there listening, at first with doubt, but then with terror
to the description the twi twins breathed at them between bouts of
extreme silence. Soon the darkness was full of claws, full of the awful unknown
and menace. An intermittable dawn faded the stars out, and at last light, sad
and gray, filtered into the shelter.
They began to stir, though still the world outside the shelter was impossibly
dangerous. The maze of the darkness sorted into near and
far, and at the high point of the sky, the cloudlets were warmed with color. A
single seabird flapped upwards with a horse cry that was echoed presently, and
something squawkked in the forest. Now streaks of cloud near the horizon began
to glow rosily, and the feathery tops of the palms were green. Ralph knelt in the
entrance to the shelter and peered cautiously round him. Sam and Eric, call
them to an assembly quietly. Go on. The twins, holding tremulously to each
other, dared the few yards to the next shelter and spread the dreadful news.
Ralph stood up and walked for the sake of dignity, though with his back
pricking to the platform. Piggy and Simon followed him, and the other boys
came sneaking after. Ralph took the conchk from where it lay on the polished
seat and held it to his lips, but then he hesitated and did not blow. He held
the shell up instead and showed it to them, and they understood. The rays of
the sun that were fanning upwards from below the horizon swung downwards to eye
level. Ralph looked for a moment at the growing slice of gold that lit them from
the right hand and seemed to make speech possible. The circle of boys before him
bristled with hunting spears. He handed the conchk to Eric, the nearest of the
twins. We've seen the beast with our own eyes. No, we weren't asleep. Sam took up
the story. By custom now, one conch did for both twins, for their substantial
unity was recognized. It was furry.
There was something moving behind its head, wings. The beast moved, too. That
was awful. It kind of sat up. The fire was bright. We just made it up. More
sticks on. There were eyes, teeth, claws. We ran as fast as we could.
Bashed into things. The beast followed us. I saw it slinking behind the trees.
Nearly touched me. Ralph pointed fearfully at Eric's face, which was
striped of scars where the bushes had torn him. "How did you do that?" Eric felt
his face. I'm all rough. Am I bleeding?
The circle of boys shrank away in horror. Johnny, yawning still, burst
into noisy tears and was slapped by Bill till he choked on them. The bright
morning was full of threats, and the circle began to change. It faced out
rather than in, and the spears of sharpened wood were like a fence. Jack
called them back to the center. This will be a real hunt. Who will come?
Ralph moved impatiently. These spears are made of wood. Don't be silly. Jack
sneered at him. Frightened? Of course, I'm frightened. Who wouldn't be? He
turned to the twins, yearning, but hopeless. I suppose you aren't pulling
our legs. The reply was too emphatic for anyone to doubt them. Piggy took the
conchk. Couldn't we kind of stay here?
Maybe the beast won't come near us. But for the sense of something watching
them, Ralph would have shouted at him.
Stay here and be cramped into this bit of the island, always on the lookout.
How should we get our food? And what about the fire? Let's be moving, said
Jack relentlessly. We're wasting time.
No, we're not. What about the Little Sucks to the Littles? Someone's got to
look after them. Nobody has so far.
There was no need. Now there is. Piggy will look after them. That's right. Keep
Piggy out of danger. Have some sense.
What can Piggy do with only one eye? The rest of the boys were looking from Jack
to Ralph curiously. And another thing, you can't have an ordinary hunt because
the beast doesn't leave tracks. If it did, you'd have seen them. For all we
know, the beast may swing through the trees. Like, what's its name? They
nodded. So, we've got to think. Peggy took off his damaged glasses and cleaned
the remaining lens. How about us, Ralph?
You haven't got the conchk here? I mean, how about us? Suppose the beast comes
when you're all away. I can't see proper, and if I get scared, Jack broke
in contemptuously. You're always scared.
I got the conchk. Conk, conchk, shouted Jack. We don't need the conchk anymore,
we know who ought to say things. What good did Simon do speaking, or Bill or
Walter? It's time some people knew they've got to keep quiet and leave
deciding things to the rest of us. Ralph could no longer ignore his speech. The
blood was hot in his cheeks. You haven't got the conchk, he said. Sit down.
Jack's face went so white that the freckles showed his clear brown flexcks.
He licked his lips and remained standing. This is a hunter's job. The
rest of the boys watched intently.
Piggy, finding himself uncomfortably embroiled, slid the conchk to Ralph's
knees and sat down. The silence grew oppressive, and Piggy held his breath.
"This is more than a hunter's job," said Ralph at last. "Because you can't track
the beast. And don't you want to be rescued?" He turned to the assembly.
"Don't you all want to be rescued?" He looked back at Jack. "I said before, the
fire is the main thing. Now the fire must be out." The old exasperation saved
him and gave him the energy to attack.
Hasn't anyone got any sense? We've got to relight that fire. You never thought
of that, Jack, did you? Or don't any of you want to be rescued? Yes, they wanted
to be rescued. There was no doubt about that. And with a violent swing to
Ralph's side, the crisis passed. Piggy let out his breath with a gasp, reached
for it again, and failed. He lay against a log, his mouth gaping, blue shadows
creeping around his lips. Nobody minded him. Now think, Jack. Is there anywhere
on the island you haven't been?
Unwillingly, Jack answered, "There's only But of course, you remember the
tail end part where the rocks are all piled up. I've been near there. The rock
makes a sort of bridge. There's only one way up. And the thing might live there.
All the assembly talked at once. Quiet.
All right. That's where we'll look. If the beast isn't there, we'll go up the
mountain and look and light the fire.
Let's go. We'll eat first, then go.
Ralph paused. We'd better take spears.
After they had eaten, Ralph and the big set out along the beach. They left Piggy
propped up on the platform. This day promised, like the others, to be a
sunbath under a blue dome. The beach stretched away before them in a gentle
curve till perspective drew it into one with the forest. for the day was not
advanced enough to be obscured by the shifting bales of Mirage. Under Ralph's
direction, they picked up a careful way along the palm Terrace rather than dare
the hot sand down by the water. He let Jack lead the way, and Jack trod with
theatrical caution, though they could have seen an enemy 20 yards away. Ralph
walked in the rear, thankful to have escaped responsibility for a time.
Simon, walking in front of Ralph, felt a flicker of incredility, a beast with
claws that scratched, that sat on a mountaintop, that left no tracks, and
yet was not fast enough to catch Sam and Eric. However Simon thought of the
beast, there rose before his inward sight the picture of a human at once
heroic and sick. He sighed. Other people could stand up and speak to an assembly
apparently without that dreadful feeling of the pressure of personality could say
what they would as though they were speaking to only one person. He stepped
aside and looked back. Ralph was coming along, holding his spear over his
shoulder. Diffidently, Simon allowed his pace to slacken until he was walking
side by side with Ralph and looking up at him through the coarse black hair
that now fell to his eyes. Ralph glanced sideways, smiled constrainedly as though
he had forgotten that Simon had made a fool of himself, then looked away again
at nothing. For a moment or two, Simon was happy to be accepted, and then he
ceased to think about himself. When he bashed into a tree, Ralph looked
sideways impatiently, and Robert sniggered. Simon reeled, and a white
spot on his forehead turned red and trickled. Ralph dismissed Simon and
returned to his personal hell. They would reach the castle sometime, and the
chief would have to go forward. Jack came trotting back. We're in sight now.
All right, we'll get as close as we can.
He followed Jack toward the castle where the ground rose slightly. On their left
was an impenetrable tangle of creepers and trees. Why couldn't there be
something in that? Because you can see nothing goes in or out. What about the
castle then? Look. Ralph parted the screen of grass and looked out. There
were only a few more yards of stony ground and then the two sides of the
island came almost together so that one expected a peak of
headland. But instead of this, a narrow ledge of rock a few yards wide and
perhaps 15 long continued the island out into the sea. There lay another of those
pieces of pink squareness that underllay the structure of the island. This side
of the castle, perhaps 100 ft high, was the pink bastion they had seen from the
mountaintop. The rock of the cliff was split, and the top littered with great
lumps that seemed to totter. Behind Ralph, the tall grass had filled with
silent hunters. Ralph looked at Jack.
You're a hunter. Jack went red. I know.
All right. Something deep in Ralph spoke for him. I'm chief. I'll go. Don't
argue. He turned to the others. You hide here. wait for me. He found his voice
tended either to disappear or to come out too loud. He looked at Jack. Do you
think? Jack muttered. I've been all over. It must be here. I see. Simon
mumbled confusedly. I don't believe in the beast. Ralph answered him politely
as if agreeing about the weather. No, I suppose not. His mouth was tight and
pale. He put back his hair very slowly.
Well, so long. He forced his feet to move until they had carried him out onto
the neck of land. He was surrounded on all sides. by chasms of empty air. There
was nowhere to hide, even if one did not have to go on. He paused on the narrow
neck and looked down. Soon, in a matter of centuries, the sea would make an
island of the castle. On the right hand was the lagoon, troubled by the open
sea, and on the left. Ralph shuddered.
The lagoon had protected them from the Pacific, and for some reason only Jack
had gone right down to the water on the other side. Now he saw the landsman's
view of the swell, and it seemed like the breathing of some stupendous
creature. Slowly the waters sank among the rocks, revealing pink tables of
granite, strange growths of coral, polip, and weed. Down, down the waters
went, whispering like the wind among the heads of the forest. There was one flat rock there,
spread like a table, and the waters sucking down on the four weedy sides
made them seem like cliffs. Then the sleeping leviathan breathed out. The
waters rose, the weeds streamed, and the water boiled over the table rock with a
roar. There was no sense of the passage of waves, only this minute-long fall and
rise and fall. Ralph turned away to the red cliff. They were waiting behind him
in the long grass, waiting to see what he would do. He noticed that the sweat
in his palm was cool now, realized with surprise that he did not really expect
to meet any beast, and didn't know what he would do about it if he did. He saw
that he could climb the cliff, but this was not necessary. The squareness of the
rock allowed a sort of plinth around it, so that to the right, over the lagoon,
one could inch along a ledge and turn the corner out of sight. It was
easygoing, and soon he was peering around the rock. Nothing but what you
might expect. Pink tumbled boulders with guano layered on them like icing, and a
steep slope up to the shattered rocks that crowned the bastion. A sound behind him made him
turn. Jack was edging along the ledge.
Couldn't let you do it on your own.
Ralph said nothing. He led the way over the rocks, inspected a sort of half cave
that held nothing more terrible than a clutch of rotten eggs, and at last sat
down, looking around him and tapping the rock with the butt of his spear. Jack
was excited. What a place for a fort. A column of spray wetted them. No fresh
water. What's that then? There was indeed a long green smudge halfway up
the rock. They climbed up and tasted the trickle of water. You could keep a
coconut shell there, filling all the time. Not me. This is a rotten place.
Side by side they scaled the last height to where the diminishing pile was
crowned by the last broken rock. Jack struck the near one with his fist and it
graded slightly. Do you remember?
Consciousness of the bad times in between came to them both. Jack talked
quickly. Shove a palm trunk under that, and if an enemy came, look. 100 ft below
them was the narrow causeway, then the stony ground, then the grass dotted with
heads, and behind that the forest. One heave, cried Jack, exalting, and wee. He
made a sweeping movement with his hand.
Ralph looked toward the mountain. What's the matter? Ralph turned. Why? You were
looking. I don't know why. There's no signal now. Nothing to show. You're nuts
on the signal. The top blue horizon encircled them, broken only by the
mountaintop. That's all we've got. He leaned his spear against the rocking
stone and pushed back two handfuls of hair. We'll have to go back and climb
the mountain. That's where they saw the beast. The beast won't be there. What
else can we do? The others, waiting in the grass, saw Jack and Ralph unharmed
and broke cover into the sunlight. They forgot the beast in the excitement of
exploration. They swarmed across the bridge and soon were climbing and
shouting. Ralph stood now, one hand against an enormous red block, a block
large as a mill wheel that had been split off and hung, tottering. Somberly
he watched the mountain. He clenched his fist and beat hammer-wise on the red
wall at his right. His lips were tightly compressed and his eyes yearned beneath the fringe of
hair. "Smoke!" he sucked his bruised fist. "Jack, come on." But Jack was not
there. A knot of boys making a great noise that he had not noticed were
heaving and pushing at a rock. As he turned, the base cracked and the whole
mass toppled into the sea so that a thunderous plume of spray leapt halfway
up the cliff. "Stop it! Stop it!" His voice struck a silence among them.
"Smoke!" A strange thing happened in his head. Something flittered there in front
of his mind like a batwing obscuring his idea. Smoke. At once the ideas were back
and the anger. We want smoke and you go wasting your time. You roll rocks. Roger
shouted. We've got plenty of time. Ralph shook his head. We'll go to the
mountain. The clamor broke out. Some of the boys wanted to go back to the beach.
Some wanted to roll more rocks. The sun was bright and danger had faded with the
darkness. Jack, the beast might be on the other side. You can lead again.
you've been. We could go by the shore.
There's fruit. Bill came up to Ralph.
Why can't we stay here for a bit? That's right. Let's have a fort. There's no
food here, said Ralph. And no shelter.
Not much fresh water. This would make a wizard fort. We can roll rocks right
onto the bridge. I say we'll go on, shouted Ralph furiously. We've got to
make certain. We'll go now. Let's stay here back to the shelter. I'm tired. No.
Ralph struck the skin off his knuckles.
They did not seem to hurt. I'm chief.
We've got to make certain. Can't you see the mountain? There's no signal showing.
There may be a ship out there. Are you all off your rockers?
Mutinously, the boys fell silent or muttering. Jack led the way down the rock and across the
bridge. Lord of the Flies. Chapter 7.